Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

(+1) 407-601.9438 victorteppa@gmail.com Kissimmee, FL. 34744

https://vteppaweb.github.io/resume/index.html

**Professional Summary** 

I am an Information Technology professional with overseas creativity and passionate

experience with a high level of academic education based on my bachelor degree in

computer science.

Determination to learn new technologies, proactive attitude, written and verbal

communication are just some of my key strengths, which will make me a very competitive

candidate.

Others key strengths that I possess include, but are not limited to, the following:

My knowledge on life cycle development software.

• Strong desire to learn

• Solid understanding of responsive web design.

My passion and ability to create apps and website solutions.

• Front End Web UI / UX Frameworks and Libraries.

• Object-Oriented Programming Principles.

It would be great to have the opportunity that allow me to have a professional development

and continue my career as front end web developer.

"Everybody wants to go to heaven, but nobody wants to die"

- Unknown

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

### **Experience**

### **Website Front End Design & Development**

Victor Teppa Online Resume / Portfolio Orlando, United States. 2020.

- Design website look & feel.
- Create responsive and mobile first web design using Bootstrap4 framework.
- Analysis, Design and Implementation of SEO best practices, Google Search Visibility,
   On-Page Ranking Optimization Factors.
- GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP4, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Chrome Developer Tool, Sublime Text Editor.

### **Front End Web Developer**

GeoSnapShot Sydney, Australia. 2015 – 2017.

- Maintenance of the web pages look & feel.
- Evaluation of new changes under new web templates.
- Create responsive HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript web templates.
- Work on changes using (GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Sublime Text Editor).

### **Web Application Developer**

MS21Consulting. Venezuela. 2012 – 2013.

- Analyse, design, development and maintenance of the desktop, web applications, web services and windows services implemented.
- Responsible for the development of Front End and Back End of the projects.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, C#. NET, JavaScript, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server.
- **Architectures**: SOA, MVC and 3-Tier.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

## **Analysts & Web Developer App**

NewTech Sistemas, C.A. Venezuela. 2009 – 2012.

Design and development of web applications to supervise and monitoring the products samples of the sales department of multinational 3M Manufacture Company.
 Software Used: IBM I-Series AS/400, MS-IE 7-8, Firefox 4.0, MS-Office, IBM Lotus Notes 8.5, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2003/2010, MS-Project, Reporting Services 2007, QlinkView 9.0, Cisco IP Communicator.

### **Front End Web Application Developer**

Grupo SMS, C.A. Venezuela. 2007 – 2009.

- Design and Development of new web applications. The most important projects developed using this programs were:
  - 1. Creation of a Microsoft SharePoint web application to supervise and monitoring the workflow of the process of all departments of the multinational company: Movistar Telefonica Venezuela. Project duration: 10 months.
  - 2. Collaboration in the design and development of the Look & Feel of web applications.
- **Software Used:** IE 6-7, Firefox, MS-Office, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2005, MS-Project, MS-Reporting Services 2005, MS-SQL Server 2005, MS-SharePoint Server and SharePoint Designer 2007.
- **Architectures:** 3-Tier, MVC and SOA.

### **Multimedia eLearning Developer**

The eLearning Solutions, C.A. Venezuela. 2005 –2007.

- Collaborate with the creative illustrator and design department.
- Develop the learning platform with the supplied files and tools using Macromedia Flash and coding all characters movements.
- Work in the design and development of the Look & Feel in all projects.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

### **Education:**

Nueva Esparta University.

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. Caracas – Venezuela, 2006.

#### Courses & Seminaries:

- CodeWithMosh.com
  - Mastering React.
    Understand React inside out and boost your career prospects.
  - The Ultimate JavaScript Mastery Series Part 2. Object-oriented Programming principles in JavaScript. 2021.
  - The Ultimate JavaScript Mastery Series Part 1 Essential ECMAScript 6 JavaScript features for web developers. 2021.
- Coursera.org by UCDAVIS University of California.

SEO - Search Engine Optimization.
Optimization / Fundamentals / Best Practices to Optimize a Website for Search.
2020.

Coursera.org by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

Front End Web UI Frameworks and Tools. Bootstrap, Angular, Node.js, NPM, LiteServer, JSON, Git, CSS Pre-processors Less and Sass. 2020.

Coursera Project Network.

Position Elements on a Page with CSS. HTML5, CSS3. 2020.

Coursera.org by University of Michigan.

Front End Web Design, Development and Coding. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap4 and Advanced Responsive Design. 2020.

TAFE Ultimo, New South Wales.

Web Design & Development (Certificate III and IV). Sydney, Australia. 2014 – 2015.

**Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

### Navitas English Institute.

- Academic English level 2 and 3.
- IELTS Preparation Course.
- General English Course.
- FCE Cambridge First Certificate English.

Sydney - Brisbane, Australia.

2013 - 2014

## Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

- Adobe After Effects 7.0 Pro
- Macromedia Fireworks MX 2004
- Adobe Flash MX 2004 Advanced Development (Action Script).

Caracas, Venezuela.

2003 - 2006.

### CASE Institute.

Web Design.

Caracas - Venezuela. 2001

### Instituto de Capacitación Técnica KEYS.

Networks Seminary.

Caracas - Venezuela, 2000

#### Luisa Cáceres de Arismendi Institute.

Technical repair and maintenance of personal computers.

Caracas - Venezuela. 1997

### Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

#### Hard Skills:

- Life Cycle of Web Applications.
- OOP Object-Oriented Programming Principles.
- SEO Search Engine Optimization.
- Front End Web UI / UX Frameworks and Libraries.
- Advanced Responsive Web Design.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript / ES6, React, Typescript, JSON, Bootstrap, Node.js, NPM.
- Version control systems GIT / Bit-Bucket.
- Databases SQL-Server.
- Basic Knowledge of ASP.NET, MVC, Razor, C#, LINQ, Entity Framework.
- CMS: DNN / Site core / Microsoft SharePoint Designer
- LMS Learning Management Systems Experience (eLearning).
- Adobe & Macromedia: Dreamweaver / Fireworks / Photoshop / After Effects / Flash.
- Video, Audio and Image Edition.

### **Soft Skills:**

- Bilingual: English / Spanish.
- Multicultural Mindset, Proactive, Disciplined and Communicative.
- Detail Oriented and Organized.
- CPR and First Aid Certification.
- Fitness and Personal Trainer Certifications.
- Culinary Skills.